Hello hi friends welcome to our channel
friends life insurance is a
very important decision in all of our lives
because it protects your family financially even after you are gone
therefore it
is very important for everyone to have life insurance especially if there are
people dependent on them friends today there are many
life insurance
products available in the market my suggestion is
that you take term insurance or life
insurance plan because it provides a
big spoon of dry ginger in a small premium
and do
not link it to any investment plan
friends your society should keep at least
50 times of your income in marriage even
before this we have
reviewed life insurance products of many companies
and in this video we are going to review for you
Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance
's term insurance plan its name is
Dish Helpline you can take it online or offline to
get it online you can go to your
website Aditya Birla Capital Talk to
or you can
buy it from online platforms like Policy Bazaar
whose link I have provided  I have put it below.
Print. Before moving ahead, I
would request you to
definitely subscribe to our channel and you will be
seeing it on the screen for 2 hours, so enjoy it so that
you get my latest video
first. Friends, this policy refers to
Aditya Birla Health Insurance
Company Limited, which is a joint venture
of Aditya Birla Capital and Sun Life Insurance Company, which is the pendant
company. Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance has been in the Indian market for 20
+2 years and if you talk about market share,
it is among the top 10 companies in India.
Before moving ahead, let's
also know about the claim settlement ratio. This tells
how many people the company
settles out of all the dead-related claims it has. For any good company,
this ratio should be 195+. If we
talk about Aditya Birla, then it is 98%, which would be
quite good. So let's move ahead
without any delay and see the
details of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Deodar Plan. Friends, first of all, let's talk about it.  The
minimum understanding of the society starts
with free life and the maximum depends on
your pension status, your health
status etc. Friends, let's talk about the
minimum eligibility test, so here it is 8
years and the maximum eligibility is 65
years. Friends, if we talk about the maximum
maturity age, then it is 15
years. You
also have the option of full life cover here, in which it can be extended till 10 years,
but I will
not call that option leave because your
premium will increase a lot in that case. Let's
talk about the premium paying term,
that is, for how long will you pay? You
can use many options here.
Single, that is, you will pay once
and you will not have to pay again.
Limited, you can use if
you want to pay till the previous day that year,
after that you will not have to pay.
Regular, that is,
you will have to pay as long as your policy is valid.
Friends, let's talk about the policy term, that is, for
how long from the time you took the policy.  The
validity of the policy
depends on your maturity stage.
For example, Ram
took the policy at the age of thirty years and he kept his maturity
age as sixteen years, so that means his
policy term becomes 6 - 30th, that is, thirty
years and here you get the option to
choose the premium frequency,
of which you can use semi-annual or quarterly,
then you can use it in Mandi, I
will search here for advance payment,
you get some benefit from it,
friends, now let's talk about the
variants of the policy, the first one is level cover, that is,
whatever MS Word payment you have made will
remain the same and after the payment, the nominee of the policy holder will get the
entire amount in lump sum,
friends, there are some other variants in quick cover as well,
such as income benefit,
in income benefit the total amount remains the same
but the payment is in monthly installments, in
which you can choose
how many installments you want to pay monthly.  You will
take installments, there is an option here for 10, 15 and 2
years and your entire amount will be paid
in monthly installments.
Next is the cover with incomplete. Here,
friends, you are given an amount in lump sum
which is equal to your income.
Along with this, you will get 0.5 per cent
every month for these years, that is,
60% up, so you will get DJ total, let's say
one crore, in 6
monthly installments. So, what is the
matter that for this option your free money
also increases a lot, friends.
Apart from this, there is an option in the health cover, Level Cover
with Soil Health Benefits, that if the
policy holder becomes one, after that
he will start getting a return which will be 0.12 per cent
of the income, that is, if it is
one crore, then you will start getting an income of 1200 per month after attaining 60 years.
Friends, this is given like a term
insurance plus investment option.
My suggestion would be that  You should
use the option only, otherwise your
premium increases significantly. If you
want to invest, then you should
invest more, such as in mutual funds
or units, etc.
Apart from this, there is an option of Level Cover Increasing Rate.
Here, your time shot will keep increasing every year at the rate of five percent
or ten percent, whichever you choose.
This is
because as time passes,
inflation also increases and to cover the same thing,
your expense also
increases further. Friends, let's option
return of premium. If you use this option, then
if the policy holder survives his entire
policy term, then
whatever premium he has paid, he gets it
back. Friends, the premium for this option
also increases significantly.
Apart from this, you can also take some riders on the
policy, the
first of which is Accidental Death Benefit. If the death benefit
happens due to the policy holder's death date,
then an additional benefit is also available for which
he has to pay an additional premium.
Next, there is Little Girl Image Benefit
Ride.  The company has a different policy for tourist
protection. If any of these critical illnesses occurs, then the
problem, which will be covered separately for critical illness, will be covered
at the time of policy.
Friends, there is an
extra premium. If you choose this and the
policy holder suffers from any critical illness
or total permanent disability, then the
premium for all the features will be waived.
To use all these riders, you will
also have to pay an additional premium. Friends, now let's
talk about some of the
features as per the policy. Here you have the option of
joint cover, which means that now you
can also add your spouse to your plan.
Friends, the next feature is terminal illness
benefit. If the policy holder suffers from any
terminal illness, then 50% off the amount will be
given immediately and the remaining amount will be given after the policy.
These are the slightest
protection. If you wish,
you can extend your time further at the time of policy. But certainly
in life events like marriage
or childbirth, etc., so let's
move ahead and take this policy
with an example. Suppose Ram whose respect  He has
appointed a crore rupees for the policy
and he has kept the term policy. Atithi
Yuva is
an employee in Atithi Hairs and he has taken the regular
option and he is going to pay on regular installments.
So in this case, let's
see what his annual premium is.
Friends, I entered all these details
on policybazaar.com
and here I have used the Aditya Birla Capital Sun
Life Insurance's premium plan.
Friends, the premium
calculator that comes up is
90 per million print. I
also entered these details on the company's website and
got almost the same premium. Friends, you can check
your premium yourself by going to your details according to your condition.
You can also use your riders there and
choose your plan according to your budget.
If you want to
compare term insurance with other companies, then
we have made a separate video for that too. You
must go and watch that too. In this, I have
also compared HDFC Life Insurance and ICICI Life Insurance. You
can watch that video too. Friends, we
hope you like this video.  You must have come,
if you have any clarification then
definitely put it in the comment section, friends, please
subscribe to our channel Pinup
and also like and share this video and take note of the hour
you see on the screen,
thank you and stay healthy.